# **AIL IMAM ABIR**



### **Contact**

#### Phone:

+8801744427474

#### Email:

a.i.abir10@gmail.com



#### Address:

House U16-17, Nurjahan Road, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207

# Languages

English- Fluent Bengali- Native

# **Certifications**

- IT Fundamentals for Cybersecurity Specialization: Coursera (UTY7NUPZ5SMH)
- Software Processes and Agile Practices: Coursera (QVUPK9F3MFNM)
- IT Security: Defense against the digital dark arts:
  - Coursera (U89RR5Y55ZNL)
- Agile with Atlassian Jira:
  Coursera (<u>3VPNN3L74ZQL</u>)
- Web Application Security Testing with Burp Suite:
   Coursera (BUU588FU23BV)

## **Summary**

Computer Science enthusiast, love to code and learn new technologies. More than 5 years of work experience in Software Quality Assurance and Testing in Agile environment. Expert in test case automation for both mobile and web using different technologies. Have a good problem solving and troubleshooting skills.

## **Skill Highlights**

- Test Automation (Protractor, Cypress)
- Jenkins CI/CD
- Burp, Acunetix
- Cybersecurity

- Docker
- API Testing, Postman
- Test case and plan
- Appium Studio

## **Experience**

Software Quality Assurance EngineerNilavo Technologies Ltd. (Offshore facility of Biscom Inc, Boston, USA)

- R&D on different automation tools (Selenium, Cypress, Appium, Rspec, Protractor, etc.)
- Prepare different test environment (Windows and Linux Server, Docker, CI/CD pipeline with Jenkins)
- R&D on different security testing related tools (Burp, Acunetix, SQLMap etc.)
- Prepare test strategy, test plan and Perform Security & Stress testing.
- Collaborate with Dev Team and Lead QA internship program.

Jr Software Quality Assurance Engineer- September 2017 to July 2020 Nilavo Technologies Ltd. (Offshore facility of Biscom Inc, Boston, USA)

- Bug verification, validation and Reporting.
- Writing test script, test cases and test plan
- Test case automation using Selenium (Ruby, JavaScript)
- Load test using JMeter
- Provide improvement ideas.

Lecturer – Uttara University January 2017 to August 2017

• Taught a total of 3 undergraduate courses, (System analysis and Design, Digital Logic Design and C)

**Software Quality Assurance Engineer Intern** –October 2015 to December 2015 Nilavo Technologies Ltd. (Offshore facility of Biscom Inc, Boston, USA)

- Test Automation using Selenium (Ruby).
- Test on Firefox, IE, Chrome, Safari, Opera browser.
- Writing test cases and provide improvement ideas.

### **Education**

Bachelor of Science: **Computer Science and Engineering** - 2016 **Islamic University of Technology**, Dhaka (CGPA: 3.75/4.00)